Now we've learned how to hit a ball inside, we've learned how to hit a ball outside, we've learned how to hit a ball up.
Now what's the next natural progression?
We're going to hit the ball down.
If up is from the waist to your chest, then down is from the waist to your knees.
Now again, we're going to talk about some of the things, some of the common mistakes that people do.
They do one of either two things.
They either drop down and so oh that ball is down, I need to try and get under it and what do they do?
They hit a pop fly.
Or they just say ahh, I'm not going to hit a ball down, they let it go.
Well, you know what if the ball is right here it's still a strike, so there's no point in letting the ball go if it's down.
So what you want to do when you're hitting a ball that's down.
Go through all your steps, boom, you're ready to swing, you still want to stay on top of the ball.
Now I know what you're thinking.
Why do I want to stay on top of a ball if it's already down.
I'm just going to pound it into the ground.
No, you're still going to hit the line drive.
You want to stay on top of the ball at all times.
It doesn't matter if the ball is at my feet, or if the ball is above my head, I want to be on top of the ball.
So here we go.
Here's hitting the ball down.
Boom, through my steps, right there, as you can see.
If I was making contact, the ball would be just above my knee.
Still a strike, the ball is down, hands are below the baseball and on top of the ball.
You hit that hard line drive, that hard ground ball that gets through the hole.
That's hitting the ball down.